Preliminary Inventory to the Gelasio Benedetto Anatolio Caetani Papers, 1906-1934
Hoover Institution Archives
Gelasio Benedetto Anatolio Caetani Papers,
1906-1934
44004
Caetani, Gelasio Benedetto Anatolio, 1877-1934.
4 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope. (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, photographs, and clippings, relating to Italy in World War I, Italian-American relations, and Herbert Hoover.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Col di Lana, Battle of, 1916.; Engineers.; Mines and mineral resources.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Italy.; World War, 1914-1918--Italy.; Italy.; Italy--Foreign relations--United States.; Italy--History--1922-1945.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Italy.; Diplomats--Italy.
Biography
Italian mining engineer and diplomat; ambassador to the United States, 1922-1925.
Container List
- Copies of a small group of letters exchanged between Herbert Hoover and Gelasio Caetani, 1912-1913 (Box 1-4.)
- Letters to and copies of letters from Gelasio Caetani, 1922-1925, mostly pertaining to his career as Italian Ambassador to the United States
- Letters from Gelasio Caetani to Albert Burch, 1914-1934, many pertaining to Gelasio Caetani's World War I experiences; and copies of letters from Albert Burch to Gelasio Caetani
- Letters from Gelasio Caetani to James Batcheller, 1916 and 1932-1934
- Manuscripts, speeches, magazines articles by or concerning Gelasio Caetani, 1923-1925
- Five volumes containing clippings, pictures, etc., 1923-1925, pertaining mostly to Gelasio Gaetani's post as Italian Ambassador to the United States
- Reports of mines in Arizona, Nicaragua, Mexico, Idaho, Colorado, 1906-1914, with some correspondence
- A report on the mines of the Austin-Manhattan consolidated Co., by Gelasio Caetani, 1910
- Miscellaneous clippings, photographs, and memorabilia pertaining to Gelasio Caetani
- Memorial testament, 1934, to Gelasio Caetani from the San Francisco section of the American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers